Hello,
everyone.
I am Nakashima Yuki,
Welcome to ProSeka AfterTalk "Unsteady, still steady step" Edition!
This is Yuki Nakashima, voice of Shiho Hinomori from Leo/need!
In this edition of ProSeka AfterTalk,
we'll look back at this event while covering messages you, the fans, have sent in.
This time, we'll be covering the "Unsteady, still steady step" event.
Ah, thank God I said it right.
When I first saw the script, I was like,
"...Unsteady, still steady step.... There's way too many 'st's here."
"Is this supposed to be a tongue-twister?"
Right, so did you enjoy this event's story, everyone?
Yep, I sure did read it right. Thank you.
"Kon-needo." Kon-needo.
It's like a "st st" party up in here.
Yeah but like,
talking about the story for real,
it's not like there were any earthshattering developments or decisions here,
Honami was just a little uncertain on this decision in front of her.
But,
"I liked the story!" Thank you.
Glad to hear.
We've had a bit of a mini-renewal for AfterTalk since April
We've gathered the comments you sent in through email
and the Discord submissions channel.
Thanks for all the messages, everyone.
We'd like to go over some of them in our program today, so please look forward to that!
Also, if you have any thoughts on today's program,
please post them on X with #ProSekaAfterTalk.
We'll also be watching the YouTube chat, so please keep all the messages coming.
Also, note that since the mini-renewal,
we won't be watching the AfterLives. Thanks for your understanding.
Yeah, they're going to have to start choosing now that they're pros.
"Shindo-san helped out a ton." For sure.
I remember that part where he's on the phone with her — how to say —
the splitscreen part?
When it shows Honami and Shindo-san side by side,
it makes Shindo's frame look even bigger.
I saw it and was like,
"ah, that sure is a fully grown man."
"The AfterLive was really good!" Mmm!
Thank you!
Alright! Let's get right into the "Unsteady, still steady step" story...
There really are way too many "st st"s.
Hard to keep a straight face.
Let's get into the story.
Let's look back together while going over some of the messages you've sent in.
First up, a message from "King"-san. Thank you for the message.
"Kon-needo, Nakashima-san!" Kon-needo!
"I was really glad to see Leo/need growing more as pros in this story."
"Both the one-man live and the fan fes were big opportunities for Leo/need to move forward."
"There wasn't a clear right option so it was tough deciding which to write a new song for."
"I'm pretty indecisive myself and tend to freeze from over-analysis,"
so I was really able to sympathize with Honami."
"By the way, Nakashima-san, when you're faced with important choices,
how do you generally come to a decision?"
Thank you for the message.
Ehhhhhh?
I think usually,
I'm able to come up with a pretty clear option I favor more.
But if it were like the story, where I wanted to do both things...
I'd probably try to do both.
But if it were a real scheduling conflict, like on the exact same day,
like I had other work scheduled on the same day,
I'd just have to choose one.
But if it were like the story,
like if I needed to get two separate things done by the same day,
I think I'd try to do both.
Like, it definitely depends on what exactly I'm deciding on,
but I tend to make decisions really impulsively like that.
Oh yeah and of course,
I usually just go by vibes.
So I can't really be of much help. Sorry.
Actually, what would you all do?
Yeah. "If I could swing both, I'd definitely do it."
As uh... selfish as that would be.
Yeah...
Would probably try something like that.
Leave it up to vibes. Yeah.
"Flip a coin." Haha maybe.
I mean if you're really stuck between the two...
Like if you don't want to regret your decision,
and you really can't decide on a clear favorite, maybe leaving it up to fate makes sense.
Play "eeny, meeny, miny, moe" or something.
That sure is one way to do it.
But I mean, like,
if it really were a "one or the other" situation,
I think I'd just go with vibes...
Like just going with whatever my gut was telling me.
Even if I were just feeling it 1-2% more, I'd probably go with that one.
Right?
If I were in Leo/need's specific situation in the story,
and the request for the fan fes got withdrawn,
I'd actually be relieved.
I'd be like, "Oh! We get to do both!"
Probably not good to think this way but I'd be like "we got lucky!"
Mmm. Something like that.
Okay. Let's move on to one more message.
Next up, from "Copy"-san. Thank you for the message.
"Yukki, kon-needo." Kon-needo.
"I was really excited to see Leo/need finally
getting an opportunity to do their much-awaited one-man live."
"I was secretly hoping that they would do that instrument shuffle for the real thing."
Thank you for the message.
Oh yeah. Would definitely want to see that.
Ehhhh? Like,
I, uh, I don't really think I'd like that.
If I really had to do that, I'd be so nervous.
I wonder... Shiho switched from bass,
and had to play drums... or guitar, or keyboard...
Would you even be able to get her to do it? That's what I'd be wondering.
I mean, if it were for rehearsal, I think she would be okay with it.
As someone so talented and self-confident in her music,
I think she'd have some pride on the line!
Even if it were just for an MC, she'd be like, "I'm not giving you my bass."
That being said...
I definitely would want to see that happen.
Seeing her get flustered like that... that'd be really fun to see.
But yeah, I kind of wanna see everyone go "how do you play this?"
I for sure could watch that forever.
Hope we get that one day. Curious what exactly would happen.
But yeah, I'm interested in where the story will go from here.
"I can't imagine Shiho-chan on the drums." Ahh, that's true.
Hmm, I don't know, she seems good at keeping rhythm though,
so I feel like she might be able to keep up.
But your hands and feet are doing different things,
so she might end up a little flustered too. I'm really curious though.
"I'd wanna see her on guitar!"
Mmmmm.
That would be cool to see.
"Everyone going 'how do you play this?' would be so cute." Oh yeah. 100%.
Ah, that would be so great to see.
So yeah, everyone, definitely look forward to the coming stories.
Thank you for the message.
Alright, I've picked a scene from the story I'd like to talk about, so let's watch it together.
This time, I chose Chapter 8.
Here we go!
Nakashima-san, could you play guitar when you started learning bass?
Nope.
I gave up on guitar pretty quick.
She understands how both sides of the audience feel now.
Speaking of Hona-chan as a leader,
asking from the perspective of, "which one will make our fans the happiest?"
and actually going out of her way to understand everyone's perspective,
I think that's incredible. Shows her determination as a leader.
It's impressive that she realizes she needs to decide this based on her own feelings,
but also realizing she can't keep everyone waiting forever.
Chapter 7 was also really good.
Overthinking makes it tougher to choose.
Ah, it's that scene I mentioned laughing about.
Shindo-san's very large manly frame here.
I was like "woah."
Indeed.
Good for them.
This is an amazing opportunity for them.
This happens, doesn't it?
Super realistic scenario.
It's okay to feel relieved!
Hona-chan is such a good girl...
You're already such a good leader!
That was Chapter 8.
So my favorite, or most memorable part was that part just before,
when Honami was thinking,
"I thought for sure I'd be able to come to a decision,"
and was feeling a little disappointed in herself,
but then resolving herself to continue being a strong leader for Leo/need.
That was really memorable for me.
If I were in her shoes, I'd probably just blow it off like,
"oh, yay!~"
A lot of that has to do with the fact that I've never really worked as a leader myself,
but that said... how to say it...
I definitely feel that Honami is super dependable and responsible,
but at the same time, I kept hoping that things wouldn't get too serious.
I was worried that Honami-chan might panic if she really did have to make that tough decision.
So that was our scene for today.
This time, the offer was almost withdrawn, but then they were told they could have a slot...
You might feel lucky, but if it was withdrawn without a second chance,
you'd definitely regret not speaking up sooner.
Decisions like that are really difficult.
But there are many times in life when you have to make those kinds of choices.
I'm not sure how Honami will make her choices from now on,
or what kind of path Leo/need will take,
but I want to keep watching over them.
And I pray...
I pray they don't end up on bad terms,
or have their mental health suffer.
I honestly don't know what kind of story is waiting for us either.
Oh yeah, Project Sekai event stories always leave some kind of foreshadowing.
I mean, of course they do, since the story'll continue.
Of course it'll continue, but...
Yukki, give some of that chill energy to them!
Well, hold on a sec, guys.
They're still high school students, after all.
This is when they should be worrying a lot,
and learning a looot from their failures.
It'll be okay.
Alright.
That said, there was one more scene that caught my eye personally.
It was in Episode 7, and we also saw it a bit in Episode 8,
but I really liked the part in Episode 7 where Honami and Ichika go to see the Miku concert.
Ichika was more excited than usual.
She was all like, "Yay! It's Miku!"
I thought it was so cute.
I thought about featuring that part too,
but if I did, I'd just be like "wow, Ichi cute. Hona cute. Crowd members cute."
So I just went with Episode 8.
But Episode 7 was really cute too.
"I kinda wanna watch it again."
By all means, please go back and read it again.
That Miku live part was super adorable.
I want to go to a Miku live too!
100%.
Actually, back when the title was still "MikuPa,"
I'm originally from Wakayama, and there happened to be a live there.
I was just as excited as Ichika.
I was like, "It's Miku-chan!"
"Miku!"
I was super hyped for that.
I hope everyone gets a chance to be as excited as that.
Anyway, I got a bit sidetracked again.
Alright, let's take a look at the card illustrations.
First, I'll share some comments from the illustration team about the outfits.
This story was about Honami realizing the importance
and weight of making decisions as a leader.
While the story showed her struggling with the weight of her decision,
the illustrations reflect a positive determination to
find the best path forward for Leo/need.
Combining that with the event song's rhythmic energy,
the outfit design conveys a lighthearted "keep moving forward" attitude.
And since this song features a sweet cuteness we don't always see from Leo/need,
we used pop
and cute design elements like colorful star patterns
and sneakers as the motif for our design.
Also, to symbolize Leo/need choosing their path as a band,
each of the three has a star chart-like element in their outfit.
We also incorporated items where the color palette is meant to resemble a compass.
This palette represents not only the choice between Leo/need's new song and Miku's song,
but also the many choices that they will have to make in the future.
Let's take a look.
Alright, so...
Who should we start with?
Who should we look at first?
Do we usually start with the 4-stars?
Let's start with the 4-stars then.
Here's Honami.
This is from that scene in Episode 8.
This is the untrained art.
Hmm. Honami has a bit of a stunned look here,
but her smartphone case is super soothing.
Is that a Shiba Inu?
It looks like one. Very comforting.
And here's the trained art.
Very nice.
It's kind of a portrait shot, isn't it?
It looks really good if you turn it that way.
Now that I think about it, Leo/need hasn't really had anything this pop and cute yet.
Oh yeah, and the stars.
So many stars all over the art.
And look, there's a dog on that building signboard in the background.
Oh yeah, and she has a compass on the bag too.
So stylish!
So, that was the Honami trained art.
Wait, that's an apple badge, isn't it?
Cute~
So good.
Moving on... to Ichika.
Ichika's trained art.
This was from Episode 7.
Ichika was telling Honami not to sweat it too much.
And here is the trained art.
Wow~
I'm losing my vocabulary here. All I've been saying is "so good."
I love how you kind of get a full view of the scenery for Ichika's card here.
And the way she's sitting with her knees up and her guitar on her back looks nice.
I call it 'sankaku-zuwari' (triangle sitting).
It's called 'taiiku-zuwari (gym sitting)?' Ah.
My regional dialect is showing.
Is 'sankaku-zuwari' just a Kansai thing?
You've never heard it?
No?
Really?
You haven't?
'Sankaku-zuwari'—you haven't?
Sorry, I meant 'taiiku-zuwari,' then.
That was a dialect thing?
My apologies.
Doesn't sitting like that feel a bit 'student-like'?
You don't really sit like that once you're an adult.
Maybe only during photoshoots.
Like, if they tell you to sit there like a student, you might do it like this.
I'm being told 'taiiku-zuwari' is standard, but 'sankaku-zuwari' is Kansai-only.
Apologies.
My mistake.
Anyway, I personally really like that student vibe here.
Also, the background... there are so many instruments!
Like...
right?
There's a guitar, a bass, an acoustic guitar...
and you can even see some drums.
Super cute.
That was Ichika.
Next is Rin.
Untrained Rin.
She's all excited for the party.
That's our Rin.
Leo/need Rin is so good.
I really love how she's overflowing with that 'gyaru' vibe.
Wow~
And that paper necklace... she definitely made that herself.
It's like in class, remember? You'd always put those up on the walls.
Good times.
And are those loose socks?
That's another great touch. It really adds to the gyaru feel.
And here's the trained art.
Wow!
So good.
This really captures all of Rin's...
charm.
I love that she's wearing a sleeveless top underneath.
And the uhh... what do you call this again?
The thing on the side of the road?
I love that she's balancing on it.
It's so like Rin.
I wanna be like "don't swing your guitar around!"
"You're gonna get hurt!"
And the loose socks again are cute.
Trends always come back around.
Super cute.
And that ribbon is just adorable too.
It suits her so well.
Ah... So cute I can't help but just sigh.
Now for Shiho...
Shiho's trained art.
THIS ART THOUGH
THANK YOU SO MUCH
Thank you for drawing such a lovely illustration.
It makes me so happy.
I could just spin around.
Really.
Hold on—
I can see myself spinning because of the delay,
Ahh, so embarrassing.
Crap.
But isn't this so good though?
She looks a bit sleepy.
Maybe she slept too much the day before.
She looks so sleepy.
Ahh, so cute.
Super duper cute.
Plus, on the wall in the back, is that a photo from the autumn shuffle event?
That's a nice touch.
Ah, I should be looking here.
This is really great.
I'm happy I can see so many little details of Shiho's room like this,
and even the soles of her feet.
Usually, they're wearing shoes,
so you don't get a chance to look at their feet.
Seeing the soles of a character's feet, especially a 2D one,
is actually kind of nice.
What am I even saying?
Am I a creep?
Someone's gonna chew me out.
Maybe the devs.
"Please don't look at that stuff!"
Then don't draw it in the first place, honestly!
They'll ask me what's wrong with me.
No, no, I'm just overflowing with love.
And that was only the untrained.
Let's look at the trained art too.
Oh, it went back.
Here's the trained. Very nice~
So cute.
That varsity jacket looks so good on her.
Also, I feel like you don't see her with an iced tea drink like that too much.
Wait, maybe it's apple tea?
I have a feeling it is.
Wow... I didn't know Shiho drank stuff like apple tea.
It really gives off that vibe.
It's lovely.
And it looks like she's in front of a music store. Fits her well.
Also, Shiho's character color is light green,
so her apple bag being green is a great touch.
It's so good. Oh crap—
I almost spun around again.
I was about to spin again.
My apologies.
And finally... MEIKO.
This is MEIKO's 2-star card.
Wow~
When MEIKO wears the varsity jacket, it's a completely different vibe,
She looks so much more mature. It's amazing.
Really amazing.
The logo on the sleeve is great too. I want that logo.
And that logo— I need it.
Leo/need.
That "LN" logo.
It'd be cool if they'd make it into merch so I could get it.
"Spin as many times as you like."
It's too embarrassing!
You usually do these AfterTalks alone, at your own pace,
so I end up acting like my usual self, which is embarrassing to watch later.
Even though this is an official PJSK stream, I just go at my own pace,
so sometimes I'm like "is this really okay?"
I'm so sorry, really.
But I really want that Leo/need logo though.
I want them to release it as a patch or something.
Please make it happen someday, higher-ups.
Please and thank you.
Anyway, that's all for the card illustrations.
Next,
let's watch the 2DMV for "Transparent Palette,"
the song for this event commissioned from aqu3ra.
Then, we'll talk a bit about the song itself and the MV.
So without further ado, released just yesterday, here's the 2DMV!
Let's go!
Waaah~
Great MV.
It has a feeling of, how to say, lightness and transparency,
while also keeping a pop vibe.
Really nice.
I remember when I recorded for this song,
Even though it's pretty upbeat,
I remember being asked to sing with a bit of hesitation in the verse and prechorus.
Almost like I was a bit worn out.
And then in the chorus, how to say...
we were asked to sing with a much brighter and transparent feeling,
so that's how the song turned out.
Also, I love the part of the lyrics that says "and on days of celebration, we'll have apple pies" so much.
Actually, as far as commissioned song lyrics go,
And seeing a character's favorite food directly mentioned like that,
I don't remember if that's happened yet. Is this the first time?
That's what immediately stood out to me.
Yeah. It's a pretty new feeling. And makes it easy to remember.
I remember that part being stuck in my head forever.
But a good kind of "stuck in my head." I really liked it.
Yeah.
Actually, I saw that on the Master chart, there's an "apple pie" note.
Somehow they made an apple pie out of the hold notes.
Giant one too.
When I first played it, I was like "woah, is that an apple pie?!"
Definitely try out the Master chart if you wanna see it.
"You think Shiho's ramen will show up one day?"
Would it?
Would Shiho get...
Would she get a pop song like this though?
I mean, I'd definitely be interested in seeing that.
Yeah, try the Master chart. It's uh...
You can, uh... they made it so you can play Master mode immediately now.
So do try it.
I can't imagine Shiho and ramen in a song like this.
I think they should have a little fun with the idea.
Like maybe she could get a metal song.
Kind of like "JYA JYA JYA,"
or like "DA DO DO DAN DO" hahaha!
If that really happened...
I'd be a bit worried. If that really did happen.
just make it an April Fool's song if you're really gonna do it.
"Would have lots of slap bass." Yeah, I suppose it would.
"The steam from the ramen would zig zag everywhere."
Wow, everyone's already got so many creative ideas for this.
Really though, I'm excited for any potential favorite food inclusions in upcoming songs like this.
And getting to see Saki's outfit here in the MV was also really nice.
That heart mark here is actually different for everyone.
It's a super duper cute 2DMV.
Please check it out, everyone.
The 2DMV is already uploaded to the official ProSeka YouTube channel, so be sure to watch it there.
Well then, it was just a short episode this time,
but that's all we have for the "Unsteady, still steady step" AfterTalk.
So quick!
That just flew by so quick.
It's already 9 p.m.
I saw the clock when I spun around, I was like "crap, it's already 9?"
I was like, "I can't just be spinning here, we need to move on to watch the MV!"
That really did fly by.
"Let's do this again!" Definitely.
"But I just got here!" Yeah!
"Don't go, keep chatting." Thank you.
So with that, if you haven't watched the "Unsteady, still steady step" event story yet,
after the next event starts,
you can read it in-game in the "Event Story" section under the "Story" button,
so please do so.
We'll be accepting submissions for future AfterTalks as usual.
You can submit your messages in
the submissions channel on the official Project Sekai Disc
ord, or through email.
Feel free to send them in after the next AfterTalk event starts.
Please keep your messages related to the events.
With that, thanks so much for a fun AfterTalk today!
See you again next time!
Bye bye!